<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-24T13:43:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bonus track blog</title><subtitle>This blog is made to keep track of my own learning progression. Besides that there&apos;s not much to see here.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My first blog post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/24/my-first-blog-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first blog post" /><published>2025-06-24T01:48:41+02:00</published><updated>2025-06-24T01:48:41+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/24/my-first-blog-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/24/my-first-blog-post.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="a000-start-a-blog">A000 Start a blog</h1>

<p><strong>TODO</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A000 Start a blog]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Arch installation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/24/arch-linux.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arch installation" /><published>2025-06-24T01:48:41+02:00</published><updated>2025-06-24T01:48:41+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/24/arch-linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/24/arch-linux.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="a001-install-arch-by-the-way">A001 Install arch, <em>by the way</em></h1>

<p><strong>(20/06/2025)</strong></p>

<p>Smooth start, slowed down a bit partitioning the disks, formatting and mounting the partitions went alright. 
Getting some errors trying to install nano with pacman. 
Figured out the issue, apparently my filesystem was read-only? Decided to retry the installation progress, practice makes perfect right?
After getting distracted by my dog terrorizing the upper floors, went downstairs to give it a retry. Managed to install nano.</p>

<p>Might’ve done another fuck up, having a distracting dog during this process probably isn’t the best combination. (edit: it didn’t work because I didn’t actually install a boat-loader lol, stupid in hindsight) Giving it one last shot for the night, if I fuck up again I guess we’ll shoot some more tomorrow.</p>

<p>After some more messing around we took another step in the right direction, I can now actually boot the existing OS. It is saying incorrect login so I probably messed that shit up now. I’m going to completely re-install it again (speedrun time?). Try to do it flawlessly this time without messing anything up. My dog is asleep so that might help(?).</p>

<p>Speedrun it was, I can now login as root in my arch Linux terminal. Spend a good couple of hours trying to figure it out clicking an endless amount of hyperlinks and reading more than I wanted on my Friday night, but not without reward.</p>

<p><strong>(22/06/2025)</strong> After not having any time to work on this yesterday due to me having some friends over and alcohol making me change my mind about going out. So here we are, after successfully surviving my hangover, decided to spend some time on it this steaming hot evening. Adding the user went without any trouble so far, working on getting a desktop environment now.</p>

<p>After running into some more issues, that were kinda a skill issue from my side <em>lol</em>, I’ve managed to get all the requirements for this extra assignment working. Only thing is that I can’t directly connect to wi-fi due to the fact that I hooked my VM up to the NAT network I made in VirtualBox. Besides, I think I’d get that working pretty flawlessly too.</p>

<p><strong><em>tl;dr</em></strong> Overall, this was an “experience”, I loved working in the terminal and funnily enough I <strong>didn’t</strong> even want to shoot myself when something went wrong. I didn’t do this in one sitting, so I’m not sure if I stuck to the 1 day time limit, timewise probably yes, but it wasn’t done in one day. I know I don’t have to commit to the time limit but it’s an extra challenge to strive for it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A001 Install arch, by the way]]></summary></entry></feed>